In the previous demonstration, the navigator gave various suggestions about what to do next.
以前の管理では ナビゲーターは次に行うことについてさまざまな提案をしました
And the instructions they gave were about things like changing lanes,
提供された手順は 車線変更 車線に沿って行く
follow a lanes, turning and so on.
曲がるなどでした
But in fact there really aren't that many types of
でも ナビゲーターからそんなに多くの提案は
suggestions you would expect to hear from a navigator.
あまり期待されてなかったと思います
In this lesson we're going to teach an approach to behavior planning that
このレッスンでは Finite State Machine と呼ばれるものを使用した動作プランニングへのアプローチを
uses something called a Finite State Machine to solve the behavior planning problem.
学習して 動作プランニングの問題を解決します
A Finite State Machine makes decisions based on a finite set of discrete states.
Finite State Machine は 個別の状態の限定セットをもとに決断を行います
In this example five.
この例 5 を見ていきましょう
When initialized, a Finite State Machine begins in some start state,
初期化すると Finite State Machine は開始状態になります
let's call it S0.
それを S0 と呼びましょう
Any pair of states within the finite state machine
finite state machine のいずれの状態ペアは
can be connected by one or more transitions.
1 つ以上の遷移で接続されます
And sometimes there is a transition back to the same state.
また 同じ状態に戻る遷移もあります
This is called a Self Transition.
これをセルフ遷移といいます
Not all transitions are necessarily possible.
すべての遷移が可能なわけではありません
For example, S4 doesn't transition to any other state.
たとえば S4 は他のどの状態にも遷移しません
In the language of finite state machines this would be called an Accepting State.
finite state machines の用語では これは許可している状態といいます
For non-accepting states that can often be multiple potential successor states.
非許可状態の場合は 大抵複数の潜在的な代替え状態があります
To decide which state to transition to next,
次に遷移する状態を決めるには
a Finite State Machine needs to handle some sort of input and
Finite State Machine は何かしらの入力を扱い 状態の遷移関数を使用して
then use a state transition function to decide what state to go next.
次に進む状態を決定する必要があります
We'll talk more about transition functions and
遷移関数と自動運転車に関連した状態について
the states associated with a self driving car in a minute.
あとでお話ししますが
But first, we want to formalize what a Finite State Machine is,
まず Finite State Machine がどういうものなのかを
with the help of a simple example.
サンプル例を用いて形式化しようと思います